RG 062:095, Town of New London
Connecticut State Library
Town of New London records
1674-1944
Connecticut State Library
New London (Conn.)
27.5 cubic feet
Administrative, church, court, land, tax and vital records for the town of New London.
RG062_095
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of New London was settled in 1646, named March 11, 1658 and incorporated in January 1784. The town and city are co-extensive.
Scope and Content
Administrative, church, court, land, tax and vital records for the town of New London.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Elections -- Connecticut -- New London -- Statistics; Voting -- Connecticut -- New London -- Statistics; Public welfare -- Connecticut -- New London; Probate records -- Connecticut -- New London; Deeds -- Connecticut -- New London; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- New London -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- New London -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- New London -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- New London -- Registers; Whaling -- Connecticut -- New London -- History -- Sources; Shipwrecks -- Connecticut -- New London -- History; Ferries -- Connecticut -- New London -- Records and correspondence; Shipping -- Connecticut -- New London -- Records and correspondence
Places:
New London (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; New London (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital; New London (Conn.) -- History -- Burning by the British, 1781; Connecticut -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Sources
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1674-1944
  - T000238
    - Town meeting notices and minutes, 1739-1911 (Box Box 1)
    - Town officers and jurors, 1772-1912 (Box Box 1)
    - Certificates, 1774, 1788 (Box Box 1)
    - Nominations for State Representatives and Congress, 1788-1812, 1836-1837 (Box Box 1)
    - Vote returns for state officers, 1802-1841 (Box Box 1)
    - Votes cast by soldiers, 1900-1909 (Box Box 1)
    - Board of Health meetings and appointments, 1806-1819 (Box Box 1)
    - Firemen's records, 1795, 1807-1847 (Box Box 1)
    - Almshouse and jail records, 1845-1846 (Box Box 1)
    - Marriage records, 1778-1909 (Box Box 1)
      scattered
    - Obligations for idle persons and strangers and records relating to paupers and transients, 1737-1823 (Box Box 1)
    - Church records, 1786-1872 (Box Box 1)
    - Letter describing the burning of New London, 1781 September 10 (Box Box 1)
    - Warrants for food and supplies during the Revolutionary War, 1777-1779 (Box Box 1)
    - By-laws, 1785, 1840 (Box Box 2)
    - Post office accounts, 1766-1785 (Box Box 2)
    - Financial records, 1722-1912 (Box Box 2)
    - Records of disputed account and bill of exchange, 1765-1795 (Box Box 2)
    - Court cases about counterfeit money, 1786-1831 (Box Box 2)
    - Notices of stray animals, 1772-1780 (Box Box 2)
    - Notice prohibiting sale of Intoxicating Liquor, 1909 (Box Box 2)
    - General Assembly records, 1699-1842 (Box Box 2)
    - Petitions, 1737-1862 (Box Box 2)
    - Records of profiteering, Tories, spies, soldiers and prisoners during the Revolutionary War, 1777-1779 (Box Box 3)
    - Applications for pensions, 1829-1831 (Box Box 3)
    - Records of Capt. Ebenezer Way and Lt. Preble of enlistments and muster rolls of men from Maine, Mass. and New Hampshire, 1814-1815 (Box Box 3)
    - Muster rolls and certificates of military service, 1807-1844 (Box Box 3)
    - Bonds, 1728-1901 (Box Box 3)
    - Indentures of bound children, 1750-1790 (Box Box 3)
    - Appointments of overseers, 1733-1850 (Box Box 3)
    - Probate records, 1705-1912 (Box Box 4)
    - Deeds, leases, mortgages and liens, 1729-1925 (Box Box 4)
    - Land record indexes, undated (Box Box 4)
    - Highway deeds, surveys, petitions, grants, etc., 1724-1896 (Box Box 5)
    - Copy of resolution of 1792 on tolls through Mohegan Reservation; land records, 1759-1787 (Box Box 5)
    - Real estate attachments, 1780-1909 (Box Box 5)
    - Records relating to the Niantic and Groton Ferries, 1674-1841 (Box Box 5)
    - Records concerning Spanish sailors, 1766-1796 (Box Box 6)
    - Records of privateering and shipping, 1775-1795 (Box Box 6)
    - Protests against the sea, 1787-1883 (Box Box 6)
    - Survey of wrecks, 1846-1871 (Box Box 6)
    - Whaling records, 1840-1868 (Box Box 6)
    - Lists of men away without leave from vessels, 1811-1823 (Box Box 6)
    - Price scales for labor and products, 1778 (Box Box 7)
    - Tax lists, 1778-1801, 1910-1911 (Box Box 7)
    - Tax abatements, 1787-1847 (Box Box 7)
    - Bank stockholders and property lists, 1826-1847, 1910-1912 (Box Box 7)
    - Insurance statements, 1851-1886 (Box Box 7)
    - Liquor licenses, wine retailers; bonds, vital record reports, Court of Common Council records, 1816-1878 (Box Box 8)
    - Liquor license applications, dog licenses, corporation reports, attachments, 1881-1908 (Box Boxes 9-14)
    - Individual tax lists, circa 1807-1860 (Box Boxes 15-20)
    - Town tax rate books, 1857-1869 (Box Box 20)
    - Town tax rate books, 1733-1734, 1745-1749, 1751-1774 (Box Box 21)
    - Town tax rate books, 1775, 1778-1782, 1784-1788 (Box Box 22)
    - Tax abstracts
      - 1789, 1790, 1792, 1793, 1794, 1795, 1796, 1797, 1798, undated, 2 volumes for 1793 and 1795; The undated volume may be 1795. (Box Box 42)
      - 1799 (Volume Item 42A)
        On oversize shelving.
      - 1791, 1800, 1801, 1802, 1803, 1804, 1805 (Box Box 43)
      - 1806, 1808, 1809, 1810, 1811, 1812, 1813, 1814, 2 volumes for 1808 (Box Box 44)
      - 1822, 1823, 1824, 1825, 1826, 2 volumes for 1822 (Box Box 45)
      - 1828, 1829, 1830, 1831, 1832, 1833, 1834 (Box Box 46)
      - 1835, 1836, 1837, 1838, 1839, 1840, 1841 (Box Box 47)
      - 1842, 1843, 1844, 1845, 1846, 1847, 1848, 1849 (Box Box 48)
    - Lists of electors, 1836-1932 (Box Boxes 24-28)
    - Old Age Assistance Tax Enrollment cards, 1935-1944 (Box Boxes 29-41)
  - 1987-023C
    - Vital records, 1854-1884 (Box Box 1)